Alexander Ulogov

Full Stack PHP Developer | Laravel Developer

I am a Full Stack PHP Developer with over fifteen years of hands-on experience. I have a strong background in web development and have worked on a wide range of projects, from simple websites to complex web applications.

I am a self-motivated, hard-working, and goal-oriented person. I can work independently and as part of a team.

Experience

2023 – Present · Magicore Academy

Full Stack PHP Developer, Laravel Developer

- Discuss employer's business needs and develop custom web solutions.
- Code refactoring to comply with Laravel best practices.
- Develop and maintain the site's admin, teacher, and student sections.
- API Integration with Stripe (subscription model), and integration with Articulate - Storyline 360.
- Tech stack. Front-End: JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap 5, Laravel Blade;
 Back-End: PHP 8, Laravel 8, MySQL, LAMP.

2003 – 2023 · Self-Employed

Full Stack PHP Developer

- Discuss clients' business needs and develop custom web solutions.
- Develop and use my own framework.
- Work with web designers.
- Maintain and update websites.
- Generate dynamic business and accounting reports.
- Search engine optimization.

2007 – 2017 · Online Plumbing Store Mirsanteh

Full Stack PHP Developer

- Help to grow the business from a small brick-and-mortar plumbing store to one of the top three Russian online plumbing stores.
- Build a very complex online store from the ground up.
- Build a module to exchange data with accounting software.
- Create dynamically generated business reports.
- Troubleshoot and resolve technical issues.
- Work with SEO and advertising agencies.

2003 - 2006 · Online Toy Store Neopod

Full Stack Web Developer

- Develop a website for a small family toy store.
- Develop an accounting tool.
- Toy market research.
- Help to grow and sell the business.

Contact

Jacksonville, Florida, US

+1 (334) 552-22-29

alulogov@gmail.com

www.alexu.dev

www.linkedin.com/in/aulogov

Skills

Back-End:

PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Python, Flask

Front-End:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Vue

Additional:

SEO, MVC, JSON, XML, API, Git, LAMP

Deployment:

Digital Ocean, Linode, Ubuntu, Apache, Nginx

Languages

English	
Russian	

Interests

Soccer | Woodworking | Chess

Education

1996 – 2001 Moscow, Russia State University of Management Bachelor's degree, Financial Management